我们是谁
Who are we?
难道我们只能活成别人期待的模样
Are we simply what others want us to be?
无法逃脱既定的宿命
Are we destined to a fate beyond our control?
还是说  我们能够进化
Or can we evolve?
超越自己
Become... something more?
1975年
你能换个频道吗
Can you change the station?
等这首歌放完  亲爱的
When the song's over, honey.
两首歌之前  你就这么说了
You said that two songs ago.
这首可是经典老歌
You know this is a classic, right?
这样吧  我答应你
Okay, how about I make you a promise?
等你长大  能自己开车了
When you're old enough to drive,
你想听什么歌都行
you can listen to whatever music you want.
行吗
That a deal?
-约翰  -不是我
- John. - Wasn't me.
琴  是你干的吗
Jean, was that... Did you?
我什么也没干
I didn't do anything.
-琴  你...  -我不知道  不是我
- Jean, what are you... - I... I don't know. It's not me.
安静
Quiet.
Quiet!
她连块皮都没破
She doesn't have a scratch on her.
也没有内伤
No internal injuries.
你确定她在事故车辆上吗
And you're sure she was in the car?
确定
Yeah.
那这事儿谁通知她
Who's gonna tell her?
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello.
我爸妈呢
Where are my parents?
-我叫查尔斯·泽维尔  -他们死了
- My name's Charles Xavier, and... - They're dead.
对吗
Aren't they?
对  没错
Yes, they are.
我很抱歉  告诉你这个噩耗
And I'm very sorry to have to tell you that.
那我接下来会怎样
So what happens to me now?
我就是为此事而来
Well, that's why I'm here, actually.
我开了一所学校
You see, I have a school
专门收像你一样的孩子
that is for young people, who are like you.
特别之人
Special.
特别只是客气话  用来代称...
Special is just a nice word for...
怪胎  疯子
Weird? Or crazy?
没错
Yep.
没错  有时是这样
Yep, sometimes it is.
但有时也可以用来形容那些重要的人
Sometimes, it can be a word used to describe people who are significant.
了不起的人  或者...
Or amazing. Or...
或者是那些很棒的人
Or just... just really cool.
你有天赋  琴
You've got gifts, Jean.
是这样
Do you know what?
拿着这支笔
Take this pen, right.
这支笔…
It's something that...
你就拿着吧
Well, actually, just take it.
这是礼物
It's a gift.
你可以用这支笔画出一幅佳作
Now, you could choose to draw a really good picture with that...
也可以用来戳爆别人的眼睛
or you could use it to poke someone's eyes out.
但不管怎样  这只是一支笔
But either way, it's still just a pen.
只是一个礼物[天赋]It's just a gift.
如何使用上天赐予你的礼物[天赋]And what you choose to do with your gift,
完全取决于你
well, that's entirely up to you.
但如果你想用天赋做善事
But if you want to use it to do good stuff...
我能帮你
Well, I can help.
你和其他医生不一样
You're not like the other doctors.
对
No.
你也和其他病人不一样
And you're not like the other patients.
怎么样
What do you think?
我不能待在这儿
I can't stay here.
为什么
Okay. Why not?
这里太美好了
It's too nice.
我
I...
我总是会破坏
I break things.
这样吧
Well, how does this sound:
如果你破坏了任何东西  我来修复
If you break something, anything, I can fix it.
不是一切都能修复
Not anything.
我能帮你
I can help you.
我帮你  你以后就再也不用破坏了
I can help you so that you never have to break things ever again.
你觉得你也能修好我
You think you can fix me too.
不
No.
不是那样  因为你没有毛病
No, because you are not broken.
十  九  八  七
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
六  五  四  三  二  一
six, five, four, three, two, one...
X战警   黑凤凰
1992年
发动机正在加速
Engines throttling up.
三台发动机效能达到104%
Three engines now at 104%.
我侦测到了异常情况
Hey, I'm... I'm picking something up here.
长官  六号卫星  显示异常
Ma'am, I've got something on sat six.
休斯顿  我们遇到麻烦了
Houston, we have a problem.
奋进号飞船在执行任务中遇到问题
Space Shuttle Endeavour has encountered problems on its mission.
-我知道你想怎样  -我才是会读心术的人
- I know what you're thinking. - That's my trick.
行不通  X战舰飞不了那么高
And the answer is no. The jet can't get that high.
加装推进火箭  经过你的改装后也不行吗
Even with the new booster rockets and all your modifications?
那是用来加速  而非提升高度
They're built for acceleration, not elevation, okay?
这不可行
Not this. No.
推力矢量已经失去控制
They've lost thrust vector control.
轨道设置失常
Trajectory settings are irregular,
可能是发动机长时间工作造成
likely from the constant engine burn.
制氧系统也已停止运行...
Oxygen generation is down...
喂  我是
Yes? Yes, this is he.
-查尔斯  -总统先生
- Charles? - Mr. President.
你看到新闻了吗
Are you seeing this on TV?
我正在看
Yes, I'm watching now.
汉克
Hank?
好
Yeah.
这是一次简单的救援任务
It's a simple extraction.
我们上太空
We go into space,
救出宇航员  带他们回来
we get the astronauts, we bring them home.
-有问题吗  -有  大概上千个
- Any questions? - Yeah, like a thousand.
没时间回答你上千个问题
We don't have time for a thousand.
我们要上太空
So we're going to space?
对  科特  我们要上太空
Yes, Kurt, we are going into space.
我们都接太空任务了  真帅
We're doing space missions now. Cool.
X战舰能飞那么高吗
Will the X-Jet even get that high?
-技术上来说...  -可以
- Well, technically, the... - It will get us there.
走吧
Let's go.
你真觉得没问题吗
Are you okay with this?
我有时候会忘记你可以读心
I forget sometimes you can read minds.
我不需要读你的心
I didn't need to read your mind.
都写在脸上了
It's written all over your face.
你说没问题就行
You tell me it's good, it's good.
如果出了什么状况
If anything goes wrong,
我会带大家立刻调头
I'll turn us around in a heartbeat.
我知道你会
I know you will.
另一艘飞船已经发射升空
A second ship has been spotted in the sky.
据了解  总统召集了X战警前来求援
We are being told the president has called in the aid of the X-Men.
航天局的各位同志们
Ladies and gentlemen of NASA,
我是查尔斯·泽维尔
this is the voice of Charles Xavier.
哪位告诉我一下最新的情况
Could somebody please apprise me of the situation?
我们探测到太阳耀斑
We were picking up solar flares.
应该是热量导致电力系统短路
We believe the heat shorted out their electricity.
他们失去了控制  通信  导航  几乎所有功能
They lost control, communication, orientation, pretty much everything.
指挥中心  不用担心  救援已上路
Not to worry, Mission Control. Help is on the way.
这没有我想象得那么好玩
I think this is not as much fun as I thought it would be.
那是太阳耀斑吗
That's a solar flare?
我从没见过这样的探测值
I've never seen a reading like this.
方位推进器熄火了
The orientation thruster's misfiring.
-船舱挺不了多久  -科特  你能进去吗
- That cabin won't hold for long. - Kurt, can you get in there?
转得太快  我看不清窗户里面
It's spinning too fast. I can't see inside the window.
斯考特  你去炸掉推进器  降低旋转速度
Scott, I need you to blast that thruster, slow down the spin.
科特  带上皮特  出发
Kurt, take Peter. Go!
暴风女  封住裂缝
Storm, seal those cracks.
马上回来
Be right back.
糟糕
Shit.
-系好安全带  我们回家  -等等
- Strap in, we're headed home. - Wait.
我们的指挥官  他不在
Our commander, he's not here.
他在气阀舱修推进器
He was in the airlock working on the thruster.
热能指数飙升
The heat signature's rising fast.
我撑不住了
I can't hold it any longer.
赶紧离开  我说了  系好安全带
We gotta get out of here. I said strap in.
不  瑞雯  不行  我们不能抛下任何人
No, Raven. No. We're not leaving anyone behind.
我不能让这个团队冒险
I am not putting this team in more danger.
他们的团队呢
What about their team?
琴能稳住那架飞船
Jean can hold that shuttle together.
可以吧  琴
Can't you, Jean?
你知道只要专注  你就无所不能
You know you can do anything you set your mind to.
我能稳住那架飞船  但在这里不行
I can hold the ship together but not from here.
-我需要进去  -热量爆表了
- I need to get inside. - The heat's spiking.
离耀斑爆炸不到一分钟了
We've got less than a minute till those flares hit.
她说她能做到
She said she can do it.
给你们三十秒
Thirty seconds.
倒计时  开始
Count it down. Go.
我们有二十秒
We got 20 seconds.
十
Ten...
九  八
nine, eight...
七  六
seven, six...
五
five...
四
four...
三
three...
二
two...
一
one.
琴呢  科特  她人呢
Where's Jean? Kurt, where is she?
-她在哪  -对不起
- Where is she? - I'm sorry!
做好受冲准备
Brace for impact.
大家
Is every...
大家都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
当然  我们都没事
Yeah, we're okay.
那就回家吧
So let's go home.
-X战警好棒  太厉害了  -好样的
- Yay, X-Men! Woo! - Yeah!
厉害  X战警
Yeah! X-Men!
好了  孩子们  可以了
That's enough, boys and girls. That's enough.
X战警今天做了一件惊天动地的大事
The X-Men have today done an incredibly brave thing.
再次向人类证明了他们为什么需要我们
They've once again proved to humanity exactly why they need us,
需要你们这样的人
people like yourselves.
总统发来了问候
The president sends his regards,
并表达了诚挚的谢意
as well as his heartfelt gratitude.
至于我本人  我感到前所未有的骄傲
And, as for myself, I've never been prouder.
大家好好放松  这是你们应得的
Enjoy yourselves. You certainly deserve it.
事实上  你们也是
In fact, you all do.
停课  今天放假
No more class, the end of the day.
琴
Jean?
你今天把我们吓坏了  你感觉怎么样
You gave us quite a scare up there. How are you feeling?
我感觉还挺好
Actually, I... I feel fine.
-汉克  -到
- Hank? - Yeah?
给琴做个检查
Would you take a look at Jean?
外勤伤员的常规体检就行
Standard medical for anyone injured in the field.
谢谢
Thank you.
总统差点就致以哀悼了
You know, the president was almost sending his condolences.
-她本该没命了  -幸好  她没有
- She should be dead. - Thankfully, she's not.
基本上都是哥的功劳
I basically did everything.
琴在最后也帮了一点小忙
I mean, Jean did a little, like towards the end,
但主要是靠哥逆转乾坤
but it was mostly all me.
你让我们以身犯险了  查尔斯
You put us in danger, Charles.
你不顾那些孩子的安危
You put those kids in danger.
他们已经不是孩子了  瑞雯
They're not kids anymore, Raven.
而且我和你一样担忧他们的安危
And I care about their safety just as much as you do.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
我们接的任务越来越危险了
'Cause we're taking bigger and bigger risks.
为了什么呢
And for what?
你可千万别说这是为了你的自尊心
Please, tell me it's not your ego.
为了上杂志封面
Being on the cover of magazines,
为了获总统勋章
getting a medal from the president.
你很享受吧
You like it, don't you?
不被追杀  也不被人类唾弃
As opposed to being hunted and despised?
我确实觉得不错
Well, you know, actually, I do.
不过是为了达到目的而已  瑞雯
It's all just a means to an end, Raven.
-什么目的  -让我们安全活着
- What end is that? - Keeping us safe.
你应该比谁都了解
You should understand better than anyone
只要稍有差池
that we're only ever one bad day away
我们就又会被人类仇视
from them starting to see us as the enemy again.
于是就让我们穿着一样的制服
So, what? We wear matching costumes
微笑合影  靠作秀安抚民心吗
and smile in pictures to make everyone feel safe?
这只是为了相安无事的小牺牲
That is a small price to pay for keeping the peace.
-让我们的人舍身救他们  -对  是的
- By risking our people to save theirs? - Yes! Yes!
真有意思
It's funny.
我都记不起来你上一次冒险是什么时候了
I can't actually remember the last time you were the one risking something.
另外
And by the way,
这里一直都是女人给男人擦屁股
the women are always saving the men around here.
你该考虑一下把队名改成"X女战警"了
You might wanna think about changing the name to X-Women.
心跳脉搏  稳定有力
Your heartbeat's strong, pulse is good,
大脑活动也正常
brain activity is normal.
至于基因数据  我得再看看
The genetic reading, I'm gonna take another look at.
什么不可能
What can't be right?
你没经我允许  就对我读心了吗
Did you just read my mind without permission?
对不起  无心之过  你说什么不可能
Sorry, I didn't mean to, but what can't be right?
太空中那场不明事件  让你变强了
Whatever happened up there made you stronger.
我从未见过像这种能量值
You know, I've never seen a power reading like this.
你真的是  数据爆表了
You're-You're literally... I mean, you're off the charts.
这是什么意思
So what does that mean?
意思是
It means...
看来要建一个更先进的机器了
We'll have to build a better machine.
不过  你感觉如何
But... how do you feel?
我感觉挺好
I feel good.
那就好
Good.
就我看来  你没事了
Well, as far as I can tell, you're good to go.
-你可以上楼了  -好
- You can head upstairs. - All right.
多谢了  汉克
Thanks, Hank.
汉克说的吗
Hank said that?
-"数据爆表"  -是
- "Off the charts"? - He did.
那个蓝毛大块头  那个博士汉克吗
The big blue furry guy? The doctor? That Hank?
就是他  怎么了
That's the one. Why?
你有点害怕吗
You a little intimidated, maybe?
一直都是
Constantly.
琴  琴
Jean. Jean...
你确定自己没事吗
Are you... Are you sure you're okay?
我不仅没事  我还感觉棒极了
I'm better than okay. God, I feel great, I do.
怎么说呢  感觉一切都被激活了
I don't know, I feel like everything is just... turned up.
-不  只是  -只是什么
- No, it's just... - Just what?
我今天差点失去你了
I thought I lost you today.
我知道
I know.
但我回到你身边了
But I came back to you.
我永远都会回到你身边
I'll always come back to you.
是露娜在叫吗
Is that Luna?
大概看到松鼠而已
Probably just squirrels.
我去看看她  马上回来
I'm just gonna check on her. I'll be right back.
别走
Just stay.
-让她安静点  -露娜
- Tell her to shut up. - Luna!
露娜
Luna!
亲爱的
Honey!
怎么了  怎么了  乖狗狗
What is it? What is it, honey?
他的笑声最蠢了
He's got the dumbest laugh.
不是
That's not...
不是那么回事
That's not how it happened.
-我的天啊  -那是...
- My God. - That was...
玛格丽特
Margaret?
怎么...
What...?
♪ 把手放入我的怀里 ♪
♪ Put your hands on me ♪
♪ 来感受我的内心 ♪
♪ To marvel inside my heart ♪
♪ 让世界更明亮些 ♪
♪ Make it come brighter ♪
♪ 我们的爱如此耀眼 ♪
♪ Our love is on fire ♪
♪ 熄灭所有灯光 ♪
♪ Turn all the lights out ♪
♪ 带我去更高的地方 ♪
♪ Taking me higher ♪
♪ 把手放入  把手放入我的怀里 ♪
♪ Put your hands on, put your hands on me ♪
-这边  -好的
- This way. - Okay.
再来一杯吗
One more?
好  我先喝完手里这杯
Yeah, I'll go ahead and finish this one.
再去拿两杯
Two more?
好
Yeah.
♪ 把手放入我的怀里 ♪
♪ Put your hands on me ♪
来点冰块
Rocks.
谢谢
Thanks.
-她怎么样了  -她很渴
- How is she doing? - She's... thirsty.
我看到了
Yeah, I see that.
你看着她像是没事吗
Does she seem okay to you?
对于刚被太阳耀斑击中的人来说
For someone who's just been hit with solar flares...
-我觉得她看起来挺好  -谢谢
- I'd say she's doing pretty good. - Thanks.
不久以前
You know, it wasn't so long ago
我们也这样在派对上狂欢
we were throwing parties like this.
现在只剩下我们
Now we're the only ones left.
是啊  原班人马就只剩我们了
Yeah. Last of the first class.
我一直在考虑
I've been thinking.
我们也许该离开了
Maybe it's time for us to... move on.
什么意思  离开去哪儿
What do you... Move on where?
我也不知道  只是查尔斯
I don't know. It's just Charles.
你们之间不管发生什么  总会过去
Whatever is going on between you two, it will blow over.
不  不会
No, it won't.
我爱他  但他变了
I love him, but he's different.
现在一切都变了
Everything is... it's different now.
是啊
Yeah.
我们改变世界  才能得以生活
We changed the world so we could live in it.
也许我们该去过自己的生活
Yeah, but maybe that's what we should go do.
但这就是我们追求的人生
Yeah, but this is our life. This is what we wanted.
-不是这样的人生  -瑞雯
- Not like this. - Raven...
这不是我们的人生  汉克  是他的人生
It's not our life, Hank. It's his.
不然你以为X战警里的"X"代表着什么
What do you think the "X" in X-Men stands for?
危急时刻  总是查尔斯和他的X战警逆转乾坤
Charles and his X-Men are where we turn when facing our worst fears.
谢谢你  总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我不过是创造了一个世界
All I've really done is create a world
使孩子们能够平和而骄傲地接受自己的与众不同
in which children can find peace and pride in being different.
我知道有些人会称我们为"超级英雄"
Now, I know that some of you choose to call us "Superheroes."
我得承认  我真不知道这个词是什么意思
I must confess, I don't really know what that word means,
但总比你们过去对我们的称呼好听多了
but it is a damn sight better than what you used to call us.
-来一起跳个舞吧  -你想要跳舞
- Come dance with me. - You wanna dance?
来吧  斯考特
Come on, Scott.
你有听到那些孩子们怎么称呼你吗
Did... Did you hear what the kids are calling you?
-是好话吗  -是
- Do I wanna know? - Yeah.
凤凰
Phoenix.
很棒吧  一种浴火重生的鸟
It's cool, right? You know, a bird that rises from the dead.
你还好吧  不然我们休息下
You okay? Hey, maybe we should take a break.
琴
Jean.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
不  停下  停下  停下
No, stop, stop, stop, stop.
异常
琴
It's Jean.
琴  琴  求你了
Jean. Jean, please.
停下  停下  停下
Stop, stop, stop.
Stop, stop, stop!
-谢谢你  -谢谢你  查尔斯
- Thank you. - Thank you, Charles.
抱歉各位  我得先行告辞了
I'm terribly sorry, everyone, but I'm going to have to leave.
非常感谢你们
Thank you very, very much.
怎么样  你看到什么了
What is it? What do you see?
我什么都看不到
Nothing.
她的变异太过强大
Her mutation has grown too powerful.
这是我第一次无法看到她的思想
For the first time, I can't penetrate her mind.
所以才来这里吗
So that's what we're doing down here?
汉克造出了脑波增幅器来增强我的异能
Hank built Cerebro to amplify my power.
现在只能这样进入她的大脑
I think that's the only way I'm going to get inside her head now.
汉克  能请你再增强一点吗
Hank, could you turn it up, please?
再增强一点  谢了
A little more. Thank you.
她在那儿
There she is.
-没错  -很好吃吧
- Yes, it is. - Isn't that yummy?
这是正常显示吗
Is it supposed to look like this?
心灵意识本就是脆弱之物
The mind of a psychic is a fragile thing.
只需轻触
It takes only the slightest tap
就足以带入歧途
to tip it in the wrong direction.
她小时候  我必须修改她的记忆
I had to make adjustments to her mind when she was young.
什么样的修改
What kind of adjustments?
就像搭建脚手架
Scaffolding.
更像是筑墙  隔绝所有心理上的创伤
Walls, rather, to keep out all the trauma.
查尔斯  你到底对她做了什么
What did you do to her, Charles?
我救了她
I saved her.
太空中那场不明事故  对她造成了影响
I think that whatever happened in space did something to her.
这个过程中  我筑起的墙垒渐渐倒塌
In the process, those walls that I erected are being torn down.
安静
Quiet!
那是什么
What is that?
那是我不愿让她忆起的伤痛
That... is what I was trying to save her from.
单人桌  老样子
Table for one. My usual.
谁在说话
What is that voice?
-不  -查尔斯
- No... - Charles?
查尔斯
Charles?
她要醒过来了
She's waking up.
琴
Jean?
琴  不要害怕  只是我而已
Jean, don't be afraid. It's only me.
你要保持镇定
I want you to remain calm,
专心听我的声音
and I'd like you to focus on my voice.
滚出我的大脑
Get out of my head.
琴  冷静点
Just stay calm, Jean.
她在反抗我  帮我增强
She's fighting me. I need you to turn it up.
我听见我父亲声音了
I heard my father.
-他还活着  -你听错了
- He's alive. - You're just hearing things.
琴  你的大脑需要休息
Jean, your mind, it needs rest.
你
You're...
你骗我
You're lying to me.
我能感受到
I can sense it.
增强
Turn it up.
-不行  已经太强了  -别增强  汉克
- No, it's too much already. - Don't do it, Hank.
-汉克  -不  我不会这么做
- Hank. - No, I won't do it.
天呐  查尔斯
For God's sake, Charles!
滚出我的大脑
Get out of my head!
查尔斯
Charles!
-查尔斯  -查尔斯
- Charles! - Charles!
琴  你
Jean! Are you...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
发生什么了  我们之前在外面  然后
What happened? We were outside, and then...
你出了意外  然后昏过去了
You had an accident. You blacked out.
我让你受伤了吗
Did I... Did I do... do that?
没关系
It's fine.
-有关系  -只是个意外
- No, it's not fine. - It was an accident.
我不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what's happening to me.
我无法控制  我不能待在这里  斯考特
I can't control it. I can't stay here, Scott.
我真得必须离开了
I really, I need to go.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
-你要去哪儿  -我要去见
- Where are you going? - I need to see...
我要去见我父亲
I need to see my father.
-你父亲他  -他还活着  我听见他了
- Your fa... Your father's... - He's alive. I can hear him.
他在那场车祸中丧生了  还记得吗
He died in the crash, remember?
斯考特  抱歉  我必须走了
I'm sorry, Scott. I need to go.
-等等  -你就让我走吧
- Hang on, hang on, hang on. - God, please let me go.
-求你了  -你冷静一下
- Please. - Slow down, please.
这种力量来袭时  我无法控制  无法停下
I can't control it when it comes. I can't stop it.
到时可能又会伤到你
Okay? I could hurt you again.
我自愿承担后果
I'll take that chance.
我知道
I know.
但是我不愿意
But I won't.
-他没事吗  -我没事
- Is he gonna be all right? - I'm gonna be fine.
-不  他有事  -我不会有事
- No, he's not fine. - I'm going to be fine.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
她充满了欲望
She's all desire.
还有狂怒和痛苦
All rage, all pain.
所有情绪一同爆发
And it's all coming out at once.
瑞雯  她身上出问题了
Something's happening to her, Raven.
她变了
She's changing.
变成什么
Into what?
我不知道
I don't know.
琴不见了  她走了
Jean's gone. She left.
-去哪儿了  -我不知道
- Gone where? - I don't know.
查尔斯  你可以用意念来追踪她
Charles, you can track her with your mind.
没法再追踪了
Not anymore.
她现在太强大  我也无能为力了
She's grown too powerful, even for me.
她说她要去见她父亲
She said she was going to see her father.
这根本说不通吧
That doesn't make any sense, right?
准备一下飞机  我们去把她带回家
Prepare the jet. We're going to bring her home.
"我们"  查尔斯  你现在状态不行
"We"? Charles, you're in no condition.
我必须阻止她  她会发现...
I have to stop this. She's going to find...
她去那里  不会有好结果
She's going to find nothing good there.
德巴里帝国就剩这些人了吗
So this is all that's left of the D'Bari Empire?
你好  武克
Greetings, Vuk.
你掌握地球人的语言了吗
Have you learned their language?
小菜一碟
With ease.
你有什么发现
What have you learned?
那股力量蕴藏在他们中一人体内
The power is being contained inside one of them.
-竟然是个原始物种  -她比较厉害
- This primitive species? - She's stronger.
她是一个变种人
A mutant.
她对此还毫不知情
She has no idea what's happening to her.
我可以利用这一点
I can use that.
如果我们可以控制这股力量
If we can control that power...
就可以复活我们的种族了
we can resurrect our race.
东山再起
Begin again.
统治这里
Here.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
你有什么事吗
Can I help you?
爸
Dad?
琴
Jean.
你怎么知道要去哪里  查尔斯
How do you know where we're going, Charles?
如果你没法追踪她  怎么知道她在哪儿
If you can't track her, how do you know where she is?
你明知故问
You know how.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
你对她做了什么
What did you do?
我那是保护她
I protected her.
向她隐瞒真相
From the truth.
说得这么冠冕堂皇
There's another word for that.
他跟我说  你死了
He told me you were dead.
我从没想过会回来这里
I never thought I'd be back here.
家里还是跟以前一样
It's the same.
一点没变
All of it.
你想吃点什么  喝点什么吗
Can I get you something to drink or-or eat?
不用  我...
No, I'm good. I'm...
不用招待我了
I'm really good.
见到你真好
It's so good to see you.
我去给你倒杯水
I'll get you some water, okay?
安静
Quiet.
琴
Jean?
这些照片里  一张都没有我
All these photos, none of me.
你从没找过我
You never looked for me.
-琴  -你为什么不来找我
- Jean... - Why didn't you look for me?
还是坐下来说吧
Maybe we should sit down.
不  我不要坐下
No, I don't wanna sit down.
你当年为什么没来找我
Why didn't you come looking for me?
别想骗我  我会读心术
And don't try to lie. I can read your mind.
我没法抚养她
I can't handle her.
我都不知道她是什么
I don't even know what she is.
我知道
I do.
你会带走她
Then you'll take her?
你都没跟我告别
You didn't even say goodbye.
我当年也没机会跟你妈告别
I didn't get a chance to say goodbye to your mother.
我当时才八岁
I was eight years old.
你怎么能这样对我
How could you do that to me?
你想读我的大脑吗
You wanna come in?
那就好好看看吧
Come all the way in.
别忘了你的所为
Don't forget what you did.
我不知道  不是我
I don't know. It's not me.
安静
Quiet!
不  不
No. No.
抱歉  琴
I'm sorry, Jean...
我的世界在那一天崩塌了
but my whole world died that day.
我也当你死了
And... you went with it.
琴  别这样
Jean, don't, please.
住手
Stop that.
Stop it.
不是我  是他们
It's not me. It's them.
你们不该过来
You shouldn't have come here.
怎么这么说  我们只是来带你回家  琴
Why is that? We've only come to bring you home, Jean.
我没有家了  都是拜你所赐
I don't have a home. You made sure of that.
你父亲当时没法抚养你
Look, your father couldn't handle you,
我们收留了你
and we took you in.
你跟我说  我父亲死了
You told me my father was dead,
然后利用我的异能为你效劳
and you used me for my powers.
不是那样  事实并非如此
No, that's just not true. That's not what happened.
琴  我们能帮你
Jean, we can help you.
我能帮你  但你得听我的话
I can help you, but you have to listen to me.
不  我才不要
No. No, I don't.
斯考特
Scott.
他骗了我  斯考特  欺瞒了我一切
He lied to me, Scott. About everything.
我们一起想办法  回到我身边
We'll figure everything out together. Just come back to me.
你说过  你会永远回到我身边  记得吗
Remember, you said you'd always come back to me.
回到我身边吧
Come back to me.
琴
Jean.
别过来  都别过来
Stay away from me. Stay away from me.
别过来
Stay away from me!
-立刻阻止她  -查尔斯  等一下
- Stop her quickly! - Charles, wait, wait!
琴  别这样
Jean, please!
琴  住手
Jean, stop!
-我瞄准了  可以...  -别开枪
- I've got the shot. I'm taking... - No, you're not.
抱歉  汉克  我想让瑞雯劝服她
I'm sorry, Hank. I want Raven to have a chance.
我让你别靠近了
I told you to stay away.
我做不到
That's never gonna happen.
你别再过来了
Please. Stop.
我必须先确保你没事
Not until I know you're gonna be okay.
我身上出问题了
Something's happening to me.
那就回家
So come home.
我们来治愈你
Let me take care of you.
你做不到
No, you can't.
你不行  你不懂
You can't. You don't...
你不懂这种感觉
You don't know what it's like.
那就告诉我
Then tell me.
这种力量来袭时
When it comes...
身边的人会受伤
people get hurt.
我不怕你  琴
I'm not afraid of you, Jean.
看着我
Look at me.
专心听我的声音
Focus on my voice.
我们会一起度过这个难关
We're going to get through this together.
我不会放弃你  琴
I'm not giving up on you, Jean.
家人之间就是这样  彼此扶持
This is what family does. We take care of each other.
你是我的亲人  琴
You're my family, Jean.
不管发生任何事
No matter what.
别再说了
Stop!
-瑞雯  -我喘不过气
- Raven... - I can't catch my breath.
不
No.
我爱你
I love you.
什么
What?
我
I...
瑞雯  别死
Raven, please.
瑞雯
Raven.
瑞雯  我爱你  瑞雯
Raven. I love you, Raven.
不
No.
人这一生  就是我与我周旋  都身处战场
We are all at war, at war with ourselves,
而瑞雯这一生都在和自己对弈
and Raven had been waging that war for most of her life.
愿她安息
I hope now she's found peace.
瑞雯到死都如此重情义
Raven died doing what she did best...
她死于帮助一个困境中的朋友
helping a friend, a friend in need.
她没有离开
She is not gone.
她的精神永在  通过我
She lives on, through me,
我们
through us...
以及X战警传承下去
and through the spirit of the X-Men.
这是真的吗
Is it true?
琴杀了她
Jean killed her?
她当时不是自己了
She didn't know what she was doing.
琴失控了
Jean lost control.
但她还是琴
But she-she's still Jean.
她还是我们的朋友
She's still our friend.
我们还是可以帮她  找到她
We can still help her. We can find her.
带她回家
And bring her home.
我们一定要这么做
That's... That's what we're gonna do, okay?
那不是意外  斯考特
It wasn't an accident, Scott.
她杀了瑞雯
She killed Raven.
即使你无法对自己  对孩子们承认这一点
Maybe you can't admit that to yourself or to them,
但事实就是如此
but it's the truth.
那不是琴  不是我认识的琴
That was not Jean, not the Jean I know.
有时  你想要相信别人不是那样
Sometimes you want to believe people are something that they are not.
然而  等你觉悟时
And then, by the time you realize who they are...
一切都太迟了
it's too late.
我和瑞雯就是在这里相识
Do you know, this is where I first met Raven.
她当时还是个孩子
She was just this little girl, and...
她偷闯进来  找东西吃
she'd broken in, looking for food.
我跟她说可以留下
I said she could stay,
这样她就不用再挨饿了
and that she'd never have to go hungry again.
我还承诺让她过上好日子
And then, I think I promised her a better life.
结果你把她害死了
And then you took it from her.
-你说什么  -你听到了
- I beg your pardon? - You heard me.
-汉克  -这都怪你  查尔斯
- Hank... - This is your fault, Charles.
她死了  都怪你
It's your fault she's dead.
你别不讲理
Come on, that's not fair.
讲理  别跟我来这一套
Fair? No, don't talk about fair.
你篡改了一个八岁小女孩的记忆
You messed with the mind of an eight-year-old girl.
你把所有痛苦与愤怒都埋藏起来
You pushed down all that pain and anger...
你觉得那些压抑的情感会去哪儿
Where do you think it's gonna go?
我那样是为了她好
I did that to help her.
-我做的一切都是为了孩子们  -行了  别狡辩了
- What I do, I do to help all of them. - Please, come on, please.
-你还是看不清自己的错  -就是...
- You still can't see what you did wrong? - It's just...
你得面对现实  查尔斯  面对自己的错
No, you need to face this, Charles! You need to face it.
你就承认吧  承认错误吧
Come on, admit it to me right now. Come on!
承认你错了
Admit it!
查尔斯  求你就认错吧
Charles, just admit you were wrong, please.
你还是无法认错
You still can't.
希望这会让你好过些  汉克
I really hope you feel better, Hank.
我刚安葬了自己的养妹
I hope that railing on me five minutes
你就朝我发泄  借此能让你好过...
after I put my foster sister in the grave has made you feel...
我不是为了自己发泄
This isn't about me.
我肯认错  查尔斯
You, know what? I know what I did wrong, okay, Charles?
她本打算离开
She was gonna leave.
瑞雯本来想离开  我说服她留下了
Raven was gonna leave, and I talked her out of it.
她看清了一件我们都没看清的事
She saw what the rest of us didn't.
什么事
And what was that?
我们一直以来都在保护孩子们不受外界伤害
This whole time, we've been trying to protect these kids from the world,
但其实  孩子们真正应该远离的人是你
when really, we should've been protecting them from you.
我到底是怎么了
I don't know what's happening to me.
为什么
Why?
我为什么会这么做
Why did I do that?
-平民不许...  -联调局
- No civilians past this... - FBI.
你们先出去
Give us the room.
你们是什么人
And who are you supposed to be?
我们是来帮你的人  葛雷先生
We're the ones who are going to help you, Mr. Grey.
我不知道她会回来
I didn't know she was gonna come back.
我很抱歉搞成这样
I'm sorry for all this.
没事
It's okay.
我们就是想了解一下琴到底是个怎样的人
We just wanna get an accurate picture of who Jean is.
说说看  你何时把她交给了变种人
Tell us about when you gave her to the mutant.
我还是
Maybe...
还是跟律师谈一下吧
it might be better if I talk to a lawyer.
很抱歉  葛雷先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. Grey,
我要立刻了解她的一切
but I need to know everything about her now.
事情发展到这一步  实属遗憾
This truly is an unfortunate development.
这话是什么意思
Why-Why is that?
因为你不惨叫  我才能更好地理解你的话
Because it's so much easier to understand your language when you're not screaming.
来者何人
Who are you?
有何目的
What are you doing here?
回答我
Answer the question.
你退下
Leave her.
你怎么来了
Why are you here?
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
没有
No.
你别见怪
You'll have to forgive them.
他们不太喜欢不速之客
They're not accustomed to uninvited guests.
请
Please.
从头说起吧
Why don't you start at the beginning?
那是谁的血
Whose blood is that?
-什么  -你衬衫上
- What? - On your shirt.
是谁的血
Whose blood is it?
我不是查尔斯
Look, I'm not Charles.
我不会读心术
I can't read your mind.
你伤人无数
You hurt people.
-那都是以前的事了  -但你确实如此
- It's been a while. - But you did.
是  你为什么来问我这件事
Yes. What did you come here to ask me?
你是怎么停手了
How did you stop?
我这一生都活在仇恨之中
I've lived with vengeance my whole life.
我从小起
Ever since I was a child,
就慢慢失去了所有亲人挚爱
I... lost everyone I ever loved, so...
我伤人
I hurt people.
杀人
Yes, killed people.
我以为杀死那些人  就能平复伤痛
Killed whatever I thought would make the pain go away.
但没有
It didn't,
不管我送多少人去见阎王  都无法平复
no matter how many souls I sent under...
于是我收手了
so I stopped.
我不知道怎么收手
I don't know how to stop.
我不知道自己到底怎么了
I don't know what's happening to me.
我失控时
When I lose control...
就会出事  伤及他人
things happen, bad things...
伤害所爱之人
to people I love.
那是谁的血
Whose blood is that?
这不正是你此行目的吗
Isn't that why you came here?
-你想让我怎么帮你  -我说不清
- What do you think I can do for you? - I don't know!
你可以  那是谁的血
Yes, you do. Whose blood is that?
-我不想说  -你伤人了吗
- I don't wanna talk about it. - Did you hurt someone?
-拜托  我  -回我我  琴
- Please, I... - Answer the question, Jean.
-别追问了  埃里克  你激怒我了  -很好
- Stop, Erik, you're making me angry. - Good!
我就是想激怒你
I want you to be angry.
-我要看看有什么后果  琴  -我不想伤到你
- Show me what happens, Jean. - I don't wanna hurt you!
我要看看激怒你的后果是什么
What happens when you're angry? Show me.
-让我看看  -别说了
- Show me what... - Stop!
军方来人了
We've got military.
就要降落了
Inbound.
待在这里
Stay here.
两架美军直升机
Two birds. US.
让大家冷静  但做好防备
Tell everyone to stay calm, but ready.
好  别再靠近了
All right, that's far enough.
我们有权待在此地
We have a legal right to be here.
政府将这里授权于我们
This land was given to us by the US government.
我们无意收回授权
We have no intention of taking it back.
我们不是来找你
We're not here for you.
我们来找一位X战警  琴·葛雷
We're looking for one of the X-Men. Jean Grey.
我很久没见过她了
I haven't seen her in a long time.
那你不介意我们四处看一下吧
Then you won't mind if we look around.
我没有家了  都是拜你所措
I don't have a home. You made sure of that.
如果我不打招呼  就闯入你家
Would you mind if I came to your home...
家人之间就该这样
This is what family does.
你介不介意呢
unannounced and uninvited?
你是我的亲人  琴
You're my family, Jean.
是这样
Look...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
-我不想挑事  -最好别挑事
- I don't wanna fight. - No, you don't.
那你就让开
Then step aside.
我们和你  你家人  享有一样的权利
We have the same rights as you and your family.
我说过了  我们不是来找你
And like I said, we're not here for you.
我们是来找那个放弃这些权利的女子
We're here for a girl who gave up those rights
她伤了一队警员
when she attacked a squad of police officers.
那些警察也有家人
They have families, too.
看来你还不知情
Guess you didn't hear about that.
我们这里看不到新闻  上尉
We don't get the news out here, Captain.
住手
Stop that.
我让你住手
I said stop that right now!
-不是我  -是我
- It's not me. - It's me.
琴
Jean?
Jean!
趴下
Get down!
赶紧上直升机离开
Get in the chopper and go!
我撑不了多久
I can't hold it!
撤退  撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
快走  快撤退
Let's go, move, move!
快走  撤离  快离开
Let's go! Hook in! Move it! Come on!
-快走  快走  -走
- Let's go, let's go, let's go! - Come on!
把手给我  拉我一把
Give me your hand. Help me!
你走
Go!
-离开这里  -我需要你的帮助
- Leave this place! - I need your help.
你不是保护这里的变种人吗
I thought you protected mutants here.
我确实保护他们  不受你的伤害
I am protecting them... from you.
你赶紧走
You need to leave.
走
Go!
今晚最新消息
Word coming late tonight that
国会正考虑设立变种人临时拘留所
Congress is considering temporary mutant internment facilities
用来关押那些
for those whose powers have been deemed
其异能会伤害民众的变种人
a clear and present danger to human citizens.
这是官方应对"琴·葛雷事件"之策
This coming on the heels of the Jean Grey incidents
她毁坏了两处住宅区
which, after destroying two communities,
袭击了警察与军方人员
and attacking police and military personnel...
我是查尔斯·泽维尔
This is Charles Xavier.
我要和总统通话
I'd like to talk to the president.
泽维尔先生  本线路已作废
Mr. Xavier, this phone will no longer be operational.
我得告诉他  别这么做
I have to tell him not to do this.
没必要将我们的成果都付之一炬
There's no need to throw away everything that we've accomplished.
要给我们机会...
You have to give us a chance and...
如果你破坏了任何东西
If you break something, anything,
我来修复
I can fix it.
不是一切都能修复
Not anything.
官方正在对葛雷进行国际搜捕
An international search is underway for Grey.
政府呼吁市民避免与其接触
Authorities are urging citizens to keep their distance.
见到她的踪迹  要立刻报警
Any sighting should be reported to the police immediately.
政府官员已经...
Government officials have...
这个人被电死了
This man was electrocuted...
你就这点本事吗
Is that all you got?
再来一杯
Give me another.
你好  琴
Hello, Jean.
你没法控制我的心智
You can't control my mind like theirs.
我跟他们不一样
I'm not like them.
我也来一杯这个酒
Same, please.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我在政府里有关系
Let's just say I have friends in high places.
你是谁
Who are you?
更应该问的是
The better question is...
你是谁
who are you?
你是那个对轮椅男言听计从的惊慌小女孩
Are you a scared little girl who answers to a man in a chair...
还是这个星球上最强大的存在者
or are you the most powerful creature on the planet?
我不清楚自己是谁
I don't know who I am.
你清楚
Yes, you do.
你是个众叛亲离的女子
You're the girl who everyone abandons.
也许是我活该被离弃
Maybe they had good reason.
因为你体内的力量吗
Because of what's inside you?
你畏惧是因为你觉得这种力量滋生邪恶
You're afraid of it because you think it makes you bad, evil,
你一直以来都被管束  做乖乖女
all the words you've been taught to keep you in line.
这些教导都是远古时代  思维受限的男人们所创
Words created a very long time ago by men with very little minds.
他们无法理解你这种强大的存在
They can't begin to comprehend what you are.
你的X战警队友也无法理解
Even your X-Men.
你能理解吗
And you can?
查尔斯
Charles?
查尔斯  查尔斯
Charles? Charles!
-汉克不在班上  -什么
- Hey, Hank's not in class. - What?
汉克没去教课
Hank's not in class.
你去他宿舍看过了吗
Did you check his quarters?
看过了  也没人
Yeah, he's not there either.
其他人呢
Where are the rest of them?
我一人前来
No, I'm alone.
查尔斯没跟来吗
What, no Charles?
如果你来找琴
If you're looking for Jean...
她走了
she's gone.
我知道
No, I know that.
那你为何事而来  汉克
Then why are you here, Hank?
你耳目遍及天下
You have eyes and ears around the world
能帮你找到变种人
to help you find mutants for this place.
我想让你帮我找到琴
I want you to help me find Jean.
我何必找她
I've no reason to find her.
不是为了我
Not for me.
为了瑞雯
Do it for Raven.
她派你过来的吗
Did she send you?
你还不知情
You don't know?
知道什么  汉克
Know what, Hank?
瑞雯死了
Raven's dead.
琴杀了她
Jean killed her.
你得帮我找到琴
I need you to help me find Jean.
我找到她  我会杀了她
If I find her, I'll kill her.
我知道
I know.
他们知道我是谁
They know who I am?
对
Yes.
他们不怕我
And they're not afraid of me?
这里只有你才惧怕自己的异能
The only person here afraid of your power... is you.
召集其他人
Go, gather the others.
如果她控制不了  就将其毁掉
If she can't control it, then we will destroy it.
这就是你要给我看的吗
This is what you wanted to show me?
不是
No.
这才是我要给你看的景象
This is what I want to show you.
太空中进入你体内的不是太阳耀斑
What entered you in space was not a solar flare.
而这也不是一场意外
And it was not an accident.
这种力量被你吸引
It was drawn to you.
是什么东西
What-What was it?
一种威力无比纯粹的宇宙能量
A pure and unimaginably powerful cosmic force.
我们看到这种力量进入你的体内
We saw it enter you in space.
我们当时追随这种力量  亲眼所见  琴
We were there, Jean, following that force.
为什么
Why?
因为这是激活宇宙万物的生命火花
Because it's the spark that gave life to the universe...
那股烈焰摧毁了我的星球
and the flame that consumed my world.
族人中的幸存者一直追寻这种力量
What remains of my people searched the stars for that power,
想要控制这种力量
to control it,
但这种力量所到之处  尽是毁灭
but it destroyed everything it ever came into contact with.
直到遇见你
Until you.
为什么是我
Why me?
因为你不知道自己多么强大
Because you're stronger than you know.
因为你天赋异禀  琴
Because you're special, Jean.
有我帮忙  你可以控制体内的这种力量
With my help, you could control what's inside you.
驾驭这种力量  创造全新的世界
Harness that power to create whole new worlds...
化尘为水
turn dust into water...
化水为生命
water into life.
你宿命如此  注定成就不凡  琴
It's your destiny, Jean, to become something greater...
演化成银河系中最强大的能力者
to evolve into the greatest force in the galaxy.
我说过  他们永远无法企及你
I told you they could never understand you.
而面对无法掌握的未知  他们惧怕
And what they don't understand, they fear.
但凡他们惧怕
And what they fear...
就会想办法摧毁
They seek to destroy.
瑞雯死得痛苦吗
Did Raven suffer?
还算痛快
Not for long.
我们以前关系不合  但是
I know we've had our differences in the past, but...
我们都爱瑞雯
We both love Raven.
对
Yes.
她生前  我们都很爱她
Yes, we did.
发现那个女人的踪迹了
There's been a sighting of the girl.
哪里
Where?
纽约
New York.
到了之后  自会有人帮我们找到她
We'll have eyes on the ground when we get there.
该动身了
It's time.
我们知道琴的位置了
We know where Jean is.
你不是说无法追踪她吗
I thought you said you couldn't track her.
不是我找到她的
It wasn't me who found her.
而是埃里克
It was Erik.
汉克跟他在一起
Hank's with him.
他们去找她了  打算杀了她
They're on their way to her, and they're gonna kill her.
还会杀掉阻挡他们的人
And anyone who stands in their way.
科特  就只带我和斯考特过去
Kurt, I'd like you to take Scott and I there, but that's all.
把我们带过去之后  你就走
I want you to leave us there and then come home.
我呢
And me?
我不是以X战警的身份跟你说话
I'm not talking to you now as X-Men.
我和斯考特会为琴而战  你不用去
Scott and I will go and fight for Jean without you.
我心意已决
End of discussion.
暴风女  我失去太多所爱之人
Storm, I have lost so many of the people I love.
我不会让你涉险
I'm not going to ask you to go.
我要去
I am.
我们需要你
We need you.
我需要你
I need you.
-我定当鼎力相助  -听着
- I've got your back. - Look...
我心意已决
End of discussion.
科特  闭上眼
Kurt, close your eyes.
我给你看目的地
I'll show you our destination.
他们在哪儿
Where are they?
她在里面
She's in there.
你好啊  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
别套近乎了  查尔斯
Save the "Old friend" shit, Charles.
别挡路
And stay out of my way.
她的所为  我很抱歉
I'm sorry for what she did.
但我不能让你进去
But I can't let you go in there.
你总是不停道歉  查尔斯
You're always sorry, Charles.
还每次都来说教那一套
And there's always a speech.
但没人在乎了
But nobody cares anymore.
如果在这里开战  人们会把我们当成大魔头
We do this here, now, they'll see us as monsters.
纽约街头上斗殴的残暴怪物
Violent freaks, fighting on the streets of New York.
我说什么来着
What did I tell you?
该死  你的家园将不复存在
Damn it, man, your homeland will be gone.
你努力的一切都将付诸东流
Everything you care about.
省省吧
Save it.
你敢动她  我就杀了你
If you touch her, I will fucking kill you.
别这么做  埃里克
Don't do this, Erik.
人死不能复生  杀了琴也无济于事
Killing Jean will not bring Raven back.
这个女人必须死
The girl dies.
科特  来帮我
Kurt, I need you!
科特  把我带进去
Kurt, get me inside.
不是只有你会控心术
You're not the only one who can control minds.
科特
Kurt!
他们来杀你了  别让他们得逞
They're coming to kill you. You're not gonna let them.
你要反击
You're gonna fight back.
连通你体内的那股力量
Feel the power inside you.
那股力量就是你的化身
The power is you.
拖住他们
Hold them!
我知道那是谁的血了
I know whose blood that was.
你对我下了逐客令
You cast me out.
现在又来取我性命
Now you come here to kill me?
没错
That's right.
你连杀我都做不到
And you couldn't even do that.
我来教教你吧
Let me show you how.
斯考特  帮个忙
Scott, a little help?
科特
Kurt!
科特  科特
Kurt! Kurt?
-你还好吧  -不好
- You all right? - No!
过来  赶紧把我带进去
Come here! Get me in that house now!
你也是来杀我的吗
Have you come to kill me, too?
绝不是
Never.
琴  我永远不会那么做
Jean, never!
我辜负了你  我知道
I failed you. I know that, but...
但这不是你
this isn't you.
科特
Kurt!
-琴  拜托  -你根本不了解我
- Jean, please! - You have no idea who I am.
我一手把你养大
I've raised you since you were a little girl.
我了解
I think I do.
她不再是小孩子了
She's not your little girl anymore.
你...
Who...
你是谁
What are you?
琴  回想一下我对你的教导
Jean, please try and remember what I taught you.
你能够控制
You can control it.
只要专注  你就无所不能
You can do anything you set your mind to.
那你就证明给我看
So show me.
走过来
Walk to me.
我是个瘸子
You know I can't.
不
No!
别这样  琴
Please, Jean.
求你了
Please.
我没法对你使用读心术了
I can't see in your mind anymore...
但你可以读我的心
but you can see in mine.
看一下吧
So look.
琴  看看吧
Jean, look.
如何使用上天赐予你的礼物[天赋]And what you choose to do with your gift,
完全取决于你
well, that's entirely up to you.
这里可以是你的新家
This could be your new home.
我们可以成为你新的家人
We could be your new family.
不
No!
因为你没有毛病
Because you are not broken.
你会带走她
Then you'll take her?
对
Yes.
不
No!
我可以更好地帮她
I can help her in ways that you can't.
谁都帮不了她
She can't be helped.
她无药可救了
She's a lost cause.
不  她不是
No, she's not.
只要有人关爱她  相信她
As long as there's someone to care for her, who believes,
她就还有希望
then there's still hope.
还有希望
Then there... There's still hope.
我就知道  我就知道你本性未泯
I knew. I knew you were still in there.
他只是给你看了你的过去
He just showed you your past.
跟随我  一起迈入你的未来
Follow me... into your future.
不
No.
武器使用麻醉剂
Set weapons to neutralize.
我没想获得这种异能
I never asked for this.
这一切都非我所愿
Any of it.
我跨越星系追寻这种力量  你却想弃之如敝屣
I traveled to the stars for a gift that you don't want.
那你就拿走吧
Then take it.
求你
Please.
放我自由
Free me.
我试试看
I'll try.
住手  你会杀了她
Stop it. You're going to kill her.
你们的生命如同草芥
Your lives mean nothing.
你们的世界将属于我们
Your world will be ours.
你要杀光所有人
You'd kill us all.
对
Yes.
琴  你得放手
Jean, you have to let go.
琴  放开
Jean, let go!
快放开  琴  放开
Let go, Jean. Let go!
放开
Let go!
那边有一个  放倒他
There's one! Get him!
琴
Jean!
Jean.
琴
Jean?
琴  琴
Jean, Jean.
-查尔斯  怎么了  -不知道  我没法进入她的大脑
- Charles, what's wrong? - I don't know. I can't read her mind.
快  出去  把他带出去
Come on, out! Take him out!
快出去  快  各位  快走
Come on, out, out! You guys, come on. Train.
你们四个跟我走
You four with me, let's go!
-我们走  -行动
- Let's go! - Come on, move!
行动  快  快
Come on. Move, move, move!
-她还活着  -斯考特  你得把她带出去
- She's alive. - Scott, you have to get her out.
你得...  不
You have to... No!
目标已全部搞定
We're clear!
最后一个
Last one.
搜索最后三处街区  我们走
We need a clean sweep on the last three blocks. Let's go!
我家孩子以前很崇拜你们
My kid used to be a fan.
瑞雯说得对
Raven had the right of it.
大恶人不是琴
Jean was never the villain.
而是我
I was.
我当初就不该骗她
I should never have lied to her.
我错了
I was wrong.
但她体内的这股力量
But this power inside of her,
非我安排
I never put that there.
我绝不会有意伤害她
I would never do anything intentionally to hurt her.
我的初衷并非恶意  琴也如此
That isn't me and this is not Jean.
我们还是能把她救回来
We can still save her.
她还留存着本性
She's still Jean inside.
离变种管制中心还有十英里
We're 10 miles out from Mutant Containment Center.
准备好转移囚犯
Prepare for prisoner transfer.
她被什么控制
What exactly is controlling her?
不清楚
I don't know.
但那个女人  那个生物体
But this woman, this... thing...
尝到了这种力量的甜头
has had a taste of that power,
她还会再回来吸取这种力量
and she'll be coming back for more.
她会再回来找琴
She'll be coming back for Jean.
很好  让她来
Good. Let her.
她会为了吸取力量而杀死她
She'll kill her to get it.
但我保证  杀戮不会到此为止
But I promise you, the killing will not end there.
瑞雯还活着  不会希望发生这种事
That's not what Raven would have wanted.
你心知这点
You know that.
你们俩都清楚
You both do.
队长  你看到了吗
Skipper, are you seeing this?
A1小队  多名敌人来袭
Alpha One, you have multiple hostiles onboard.
他们正向车尾移动
They're heading towards the back.
-打开四号门  五号门  -收到
- Open four to five. - Copy that.
你们俩  跟我来
All right, you two, come with me.
其余人留守  看住犯人
The rest of you, stay here, guard the prisoners!
别犯傻  你们需要我们
Don't be fools! You need our help!
快  锁门
Lock it down! Now!
可恶的变种来救你们了
Goddamn muties come to spring you.
他们不是变种人
They're not mutants.
放了我们  你们会需要我们
Free us, you're going to need our help.
只有我们出手  你们才能活命
We're the only chance you have.
闭嘴吧
Keep your mouth shut.
求救  求救
Mayday! Mayday!
汇报一下变种人敌情
What's the status on those mutants?
我们正在撤退  他们不是...
We're falling back now! They're not...
什么
What?
他们不是什么
They're not what?
-他们不是变种人  -他们来找琴了
- They're not mutants! - They're here for Jean.
准备开火
Get ready to open fire!
你家孩子没看错我们
Your kid was right about us.
我们能救你们
We could help you!
放开我们
Please!
开火
Fire!
后面还有敌人
There's more!
我们的目标只是那个女人  让开
We only want the girl. Step aside.
不要
No!
你干什么
What are you doing?
瑞雯还活着  就一定会这么做
What Raven would have.
斯考特  把我带到琴那里
Scott, get me to Jean!
塞琳
Selene!
汉克
Hank!
帮一下暴风女
Help Storm!
不不  别死啊
No, no, no, no, no, please.
别死啊  别啊
Don't die. No.
到了  到了
That's it, that's it, that's it.
斯考特  守住入口
Scott, guard the entrance.
琴  醒醒
Jean, wake up.
琴  醒醒  你得赶紧醒过来
Jean, wake up. You have to wake up now.
汉克
Hank!
我不想跟你打
I have no desire to fight you.
这话我常听
I get that a lot.
你之前想让她死
You wanted her dead.
我改变心意了
I had a change of heart.
我当时是想保护你
I was trying to protect you.
我不想让你经历那些痛苦  但是
I was trying to keep the pain away, but...
你只是将其埋藏起来了
You just buried it.
琴
Jean.
这是哪儿
Where...?
这是在我的大脑里吗
Are we inside my mind?
这里比我的大脑要平静
It's more peaceful than mine.
我当年那么对你  我很抱歉
I'm so sorry for what I did to you.
我知道
I know.
我当时只是一心想保护你
All I ever wanted was to protect you
让你过上常人的生活
and give you what you deserved.
拥有一个美好的童年
What every child deserves.
一个美好的家
A family.
对
Yeah.
我知道你是出于爱才这样做
I know you did what you did out of love.
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
我知道我现在要做什么了
I know what I need to do now.
做什么
And what is that?
保护我的家人
Protect my family.
琴  琴
Jean. Jean.
你想要这股力量吗
You want this power?
那就给你
You're gonna get it.
琴
Jean!
你无法控制
You can't control it.
如果你杀了我  也会杀死大家
If you kill me, you'll kill them all.
情义使你不堪一击
Your emotions make you weak.
琴
Jean.
够了
Enough.
琴
Jean!
你错了
You're wrong.
情义使我无所不能
My emotions make me strong.
她消失了
She's gone.
她
She...
她自由了
She's free.
琴·葛雷天赋青少年学校
我清楚自己是谁了
I know who I am now.
我不是别人眼中期待的模样
I am not simply what others want me to be.
我不是无法逃脱宿命的人
I am not destined to a fate I can't control.
我进化超越了
I evolved beyond this world.
这不是我的终结
This is not the end of me...
也不是X战警的终结
or the X-Men.
这是一个崭新的开始
It's a new beginning.
别跑  安全第一
Hey, slow down. Safety first.
退休生活如何
How's retirement treating you?
你怎么来了  埃里克
What are you doing here, Erik?
我来见见老朋友
I came to see an old friend.
来一局如何
Fancy a game?
今天不来了  谢了
No, not today. Thank you.
很久之前  你救了我一命
A long time ago, you saved my life.
然后给了我一个家
Then you offered me a home.
我如今也想这么做
I'd like to do the same for you.
就来一局
Just one game.
毕竟故交一场
For old times' sake.
我会手下留情
I'll go easy on you.
你可不会
No, you won't.
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译    Ievo    Margaery   余欢  77 imyours
翻译   兔牙Bobby猫☆ 开学欢乐多！！
校对    兔牙Bobby猫★ Forever21
时间轴   兔牙Bobby猫☆ DNA重编辑
后期     8T
总监    兔牙Bobby猫 ♥ 基因新变异